Josh Cesana

joshuacesana@gmail.com | 925-200-3164 | San Ramon, CA | github.com/JCesana | linkedin.com/in/josh-cesana/

SUMMARY

Motivated full stack web developer with experience creating custom websites using JavaScript (React), Ruby on Rails, HTML, and CSS. Organized and focused with a strong passion to continuously learn new technologies. Former Operations Manager experienced working in teams with strong attention to detail.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Flatiron School, Online Coding Bootcamp Full Stack Web Development

May 2018 - January 2019

React News - React, Redux, HTML, CSS Video Github

News client for searching, viewing, and saving articles.

- Implemented create-react-app, Redux middleware with a Rails API backend
- Styled with MaterializeCSS framework
- Dynamic routing with react-router
- Fetched data from newsapi.org API
- Designed database schema using ActiveRecord

Rails Recipes - Rails, JavaScript, HTML, CSS Video Github

Recipes client for creating, viewing, updating, and deleting recipes.

- Designed client side with Bulma and custom CSS
- Built API functionality using Ruby on Rails and MVC pattern
- Implemented Devise for user authentication
- Implemented Active Storage for image attachment
- Implemented cocoon for added form functionality

Task Buddy - Ruby, Sinatra, HTML, CSS Video Github

To do list client for adding and deleting tasks.

- Built database schema and configured ActiveRecord associations
- Built RESTful APIs using Sinatra framework and Rake tasks
- Used Bcrypt for secure password storage

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript | HTML5 | CSS | Ruby | SQL

Frameworks: React | Redux | Node | Rails | Sinatra | Bootstrap | Bulma | MaterializeCSS

Tools: Atom | Sublime | Git | Photoshop

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Operations Manager

February 2016 - May 2018

Piace Carta, LLC

- Oversaw the creation and implementation of online retail website
- Trained and supported staff
- Monitored product inventory

Business Owner - Self Employed

May 2013 - February 2016

Lifebox Cases, LLC

- Exceeded \$1,000,000 in sales
- Managed A/P, A/R, billing, purchasing, cost analysis, marketing research, and taxes
- Hired, trained, and supervised new team members

Web Application Developer

May 2011 - May 2013

Global Logistics Village, Inc.

- Enhanced user interface for large scale online service
- Experienced positive exposure to working with development team in collaborative environment
- Acquired valuable technical skills, strengthening attention to detail

Sales Coordinator

December 2007 - May 2011

Global Logistics Village, Inc.

- Contacted executive level members at target corporations
- Identified needs of target corporations
- Proposed solutions with custom logistics system

Loan Officer

December 2006 - December 2007

Home 123, Inc.

- Secured Top Closer Award (by monthly volume)
- Originated new customer loans through networking, leads, and cold calling
- Coordinated with clients, managers, underwriters, and appraisers in the delivery of loans

Staff Accountant

May 2005 - December 2006

KSJG, LLP

- Started, assisted, and completed audit reports
- Assisted in the audit of organizations from various industries
- Coordinated data collection, workflow, and time management with clients

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

May 2018 - January 2019

Full Stack Web Development Online Bootcamp

Biola University

August 2000 - May 2004

BS in Business - Accounting

INTERESTS

Cycling, Basketball, Live Symphony Concerts, French Bulldog Meetups, Crosswords